A Guide to the Frank Harris Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7453-a
Frank Harris Collection 1926-1930
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7453-a
12 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1964 Apr 29
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Frank Harris to Brice O. Taylor, 1926 Nov 8; TLS, 1 p.
    [Sends second volume of
    My Life and Loves
    , which he regards as his best work; will send the first volume when money is received.]
  - Frank Harris to Brice O. Taylor, 1926 Dec 29; TLS, 1 p.
    [Asking agent in America to send volume one of [
    ]; says customs would not allow shipping from France because of nude pictures; regards volumes two and three of [
    ] as his best work; is ill with bronchitis.]
  - Frank Harris to Brice O. Taylor, 1927 Aug 29; TLS, 1 p.
    [Agrees with comments on
    comments on religion, war, the Sacco and Vanzetti case, and human stupidity; begs forgiveness for 'scrawl,' the result of near blindness.]
  - Frank Harris to Brice O. Taylor, 1927 Nov 22; TLS, 1 p.
    [Requests Edna Millay's "Renasence"; wishes to disprove claim that it is "the best modern poem"; also requests the best work of Edwin A. Robinson, with whom he is not familiar.]
  - Frank Harris to Brice O. Taylor, 1927 Dec 24; TLS, 1 p.
    [Does not rate Millay and Robinson as highly as Taylor does; looks forward to receiving the books in order to favorably revise his opinion of them.]
  - Frank Harris to Brice O. Taylor, 1928 Feb 28; TLS, 1 p.
    [Would welcome the book showing trend of American poetry but doubts that he and Taylor would agree; disparages [Thomas] Hardy's work, especially the silliness of
    Tess of the d'Ubervilles
    complains that Hardy was wealthy and highly honored while he is hard working but poor; comments on sonnet by Lizette Woodworth Reese. ]
  - Frank Harris to Brice O. Taylor, 1928 Apr 2; TLS, 1 p.
    [Looks forward to book he is sending; does not think Theodore Dreiser capable of writing about Russia, recommends book by A[lexander] Berkman and [Emma] Goldman. ]
  - Frank Harris to Brice O. Taylor, 1929 Jun 6; TLS, 1 p.
    [Wishes to renew relationship after two years of illness; gives prices for four volumes of
    mentions his secretary left, taking the typescript copy of the fourth volume with her; hopes to publish
    Pantopia
    in the fall.]
  - Frank Harris to Brice O. Taylor, 1929 Jul 6; TLS, 1 p.
    [Will send
    when printed; requests [E.W.] Howe's comments and his book; has written a volume of "Essays" and the sixth volume of
    [Contemporary] Portraits
    asks if he could find a publisher willing to pay advance on royalties.]
  - Frank Harris to Brice O. Taylor, 1930 Apr 16; TL, 1 p.
    [Comments on
    The Lies and Libels of Frank Harris
    disputes claim that he is "half-Jew, half-Irish"; inquires about Stanley Westal and Frank Dobie who have criticized his "cowboy book"; expects
    to be published in New York in the fall; says
    is providing a good income; complains that censors prevent him from sending it to him.]
  - Frank Harris to Brice O. Taylor, 1930 May 22; TL, 1 p.
    [Pleased that he liked
    Confessional
    asks that he defend him from attacks by Frank Dobie and Stanley Vestal; feels that his own mistakes about dates and places are a result of the passage of sixty years; comments on progress of
    which is being undermined by the censors; had hoped it would equal
    Montes [the Matador]
    and
    The Miracle of Stigmata
    . ]
  - Frank Harris to Brice O. Taylor, 1930 Jul 12; TL, 1 p.
    [Pleased that he agrees with idea of adding Lord Alfred Douglas' confession to
    Oscar Wilde: [His Life and Times]
    denies Wilde translated
    Petronius Arbiter
    comments on
    Life of Shaw